<?xml version="1.0"?>
<configuration>
	<placeholders>
		<placeholder id="template_name">Salesforce to Salesforce User Migration</placeholder>
	</placeholders>
	<sections>
		<section id="use_case">
As a Salesforce admin I want to migrate users between two Salesfoce orgs.

This Anypoint Template should serve as a foundation for the process of migrating users from one Salesfoce instance to another, being able to specify filtering criterias and desired behaviour when a user already exists in the destination org. 

As implemented, this Anypoint Template leverages the [Batch Module](http://www.mulesoft.org/documentation/display/current/Batch+Processing).
The batch job is divided in Input, Process and On Complete stages.
During the Input stage the Anypoint Template will go to the SalesForce Org A and query all the existing users that match the filter criteria.
The last step of the Process stage will group the users and create them in SFDC Org B.
Finally during the On Complete stage the Anypoint Template will both output statistics data into the console and send a notification email with the results of the batch excecution. 
		</section>
		<section id="considerations">
<![CDATA[
There are a couple of things you should take into account before running this Anypoint Template:
1. **Users cannot be deleted in SalesForce:** For now, the only thing to do regarding users removal is disabling/deactivating them, but this won't make the username available for a new user.
2. **Each user needs to be associated to a Profile:** SalesForce's profiles are what define the permissions the user will have for manipulating data and other users. Each SalesForce account has its own profiles. In this Anypoint Template you will find a processor labeled *assignProfileId and Username to the User* where to map your Profile Ids from the source account to the ones in the target account. Note that for the integration test to run properly, you should change the constant *DEFAULT_PROFILE_ID* in *BusinessLogicTestIT* to one that's valid in your source test organization.
3. **Working with sandboxes for the same account**: Although each sandbox should be a completely different environment, Usernames cannot be repeated in different sandboxes, i.e. if you have a user with username *bob.dylan* in *sandbox A*, you will not be able to create another user with username *bob.dylan* in *sandbox B*. If you are indeed working with Sandboxes for the same SalesForce account you will need to map the source username to a different one in the target sandbox, for this purpose, please refer to the processor labeled *assign ProfileId and Username to the User*.
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="run_it">
<![CDATA[

In any of the ways you would like to run this Anypoint Template this is an example of the output you'll see after hitting the HTTP endpoint:

<pre>
<h1>Batch Process initiated</h1>
<b>ID:</b>6eea3cc6-7c96-11e3-9a65-55f9f3ae584e<br/>
<b>Records to Be Processed: </b>9<br/>
<b>Start execution on: </b>Mon Jan 13 18:05:33 GMT-03:00 2014
</pre>
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="running_on_cloudhub">
<![CDATA[
Once your app is all set and started, supposing you choose as domain name `sfdcusermigration` to trigger the use case you just need to hit `http://sfdcusermigration.cloudhub.io/migrateUsers` and report will be sent to the emails configured.
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="running_on_standalone">
<![CDATA[
After this, to trigger the use case you just need to hit the local http endpoint with the port you configured in your file. If this is, for instance, `9090` then you should hit: `http://localhost:9090/migrateUsers` and this will create a CSV report and send it to the mails set.
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="application_configuration">
		<![CDATA[
+ http.port `9090`
+ startingDate `2014-01-30'T'00:00:00.000'Z'`

#### SalesForce Connector configuration for company A
+ sfdc.a.username `bob.dylan@orga`
+ sfdc.a.password `DylanPassword123`
+ sfdc.a.securityToken `avsfwCUl7apQs56Xq2AKi3X`
+ sfdc.a.url `https://login.salesforce.com/services/Soap/u/26.0`

#### SalesForce Connector configuration for company B
+ sfdc.b.username `joan.baez@orgb`
+ sfdc.b.password `JoanBaez456`
+ sfdc.b.securityToken `ces56arl7apQs56XTddf34X`
+ sfdc.b.url `https://login.salesforce.com/services/Soap/u/26.0`


#### eMail Details
+ mail.from `batch.user.migration%40mulesoft.com`
+ mail.to `your.username@youremaildomain.com`
+ mail.subject `Batch Job Finished Report`
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="api_calls">
		<![CDATA[
Salesforce imposes limits on the number of API Calls that can be made. Therefore calculating this amount may be an important factor to consider. The Anypoint Template calls to the API can be calculated using the formula:

***1 + X + X / 200***

Being ***X*** the number of Users to be synchronized on each run. 

The division by ***200*** is because, by default, Users are gathered in groups of 200 for each Upsert API Call in the commit step. Also consider that this calls are executed repeatedly every polling cycle.	

For instance if 10 records are fetched from origin instance, then 12 api calls will be made (1 + 10 + 1).
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="default_endpoints_xml">
		<![CDATA[
This is the file where you will found the inbound and outbound sides of your integration app.
This Anypoint Template has only an [HTTP Inbound Endpoint](http://www.mulesoft.org/documentation/display/current/HTTP+Endpoint+Reference) as the way to trigger the use case.

$H$H#  Inbound Flow
**HTTP Inbound Endpoint** - Start Report Generation
+ `${http.port}` is set as a property to be defined either on a property file or in CloudHub environment variables.
+ The path configured by default is `migrateusers` and you are free to change for the one you prefer.
+ The host name for all endpoints in your CloudHub configuration should be defined as `localhost`. CloudHub will then route requests from your application domain URL to the endpoint.
+ The endpoint is configured as a *request-response* since as a result of calling it the response will be the total of Users migrated and filtered by the criteria specified.
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="default_business_logic_xml">
		<![CDATA[
Functional aspect of the Anypoint Template is implemented on this XML, directed by one flow responsible of excecuting the logic.
For the pourpose of this particular Anypoint Template the *mainFlow* just excecutes the Batch Job which handles all the logic of it.
This flow has Exception Strategy that basically consists on invoking the *defaultChoiseExceptionStrategy* defined in *errorHandling.xml* file.
]]>
		</section>
	</sections>
</configuration>